Richard Kennedy

Frontend developer







PROFILE

I'm an Australian who moved to Stockholm in 2015 with my Swedish partner. I am a passionate, thoughtful and positive person who is very goal-orientated. I do enjoy bringing that energy into the teams that I work with and everywhere I go. I have been an electrician for 10 years and decided I wanted to follow a new passion of mine since the move to Stockholm. It led me to Hyper Island were I study Frontend Development. currently interning at Mobiento / Deloitte Digital and ready to secure a junior developer role and start my next journey.

EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer Intern

Mobiento / Deloitte Digital

Sep 2022 - Present, Stockholm

Building an Unsplash clone as my intern task. And continuing to really deep dive into React | Typescript | Unit Testing | Bitbucket

Frontend Development

Aug 2021 - Present, Stockholm

Currently studying frontend development at Hyper Island. Project-based learning both individually and in teams. Adapting an agile mindset to my development process and learning to create beautiful, functional, practical and all in between - web applications.

Industrial/Commercial Electrician

Norrsken Elinstallationer

Jan 2016 - Aug 2021 - 5 years, Stockholm

Supervisor Construction Electrician

Civmec Engineering & Goodline electrical

Jan 2015 - Dec 2015 - 1 year, Port Hedland, Australia

Apprentice Electrician

Changeovers PTY LTD

Jan 2011 - jan 2015 - 4 years, Perth, Australia

CONTACT

Richardgrahamkennedy@gmail.com

+46 73 833 29 99

Education

Frontend development Full-time Diploma

Hyper Island

2021 - 2023 Stockholm, Sweden

CERTIFICATE III in Electrotechnology

Electrician

North Metropolitan TAFE 2011 - 2014, Perth Australia

Industry Knowledge

Product Design & development Agile development process Working in teams SEO & Accessibility Wireframing Prototyping

Skills

Design Research

HTML, CSS, SCSS, Tailwind, Javascript, Phaser.JS, React.JS, Figma, GitHub, MongoDB, Typescript, Unit-testing

Hobbies

Coding, Surfing, Snowboarding, Coffee, Interior design, Fashion, MUSIC

Language

English (professional)
Swedish (learning)

Reference

Will happily provide on request

Richard Kennedy

Frontend developer

Professional Highlights

2022 -

Unsplash Clone - (React / Typescript / Tailwind / Jest)

Re-creating Unsplash using the Unsplash API.

This project comes with a clean UI that features a search-bar, the classic unsplash masonry grid layout for my image gallery, a category list that routes dynamically, placeholders for slow loading and its all responsive. What I learned the most from this project is the importance of testing and how to write a way cleaner code for eg - useContext as oppose to prop drilling, reusing components and functionality.

2022 -

E-commerce Happenings - An experience package

Frontend & Backend (React / Tailwind / JavaScript / MongoDB) I collaborated in a team to build and deploy an e-commerce application that provides experiences such as whale-watching, salsa dancing etc, where all products chosen are taken through a checkout process. I was responsible for the database architecture, developing user friendly interactions, responsiveness, rendering the items in the database and creating an individual information page for selected items.

2022 -

3D GAME WHACK-A-CRAB

Frontend (JavaScript / A-frame)

I built and deployed a 3D game that I presented at the Hyper Island game conference. I implemented 3D models and a 3D environment into the game that is interactable through the use of JavaScript and A-Frame functionalities.

2022 -

WEBSITE Travel advice

Frontend & Backend (Next.js / React / Tailwind / MongoDB)

I Built and deployed an application that allowed users to search for a country or city and be given advice on where to eat, stay and discover. I created a database that stores content and uses a frontend stack of Next.js, React and Tailwind to render the content.

2021 -

ARCADE GAME Space Invaders

Frontend (JavaScript / Phaser.js)

I collaborated in a small team to build and deploy a 2D game using Phaser.js. This game was to be presented to the Hyper Island FED23 class once complete. I was responsible for creating a parallax background, shooter functionality, invaders to disappear on collision and a scoreboard.

